Babies start learning from birth.
يبدأ الأطفال التعلم منذ الولادة.
They learned through the experiences and interactions they have with the people in
يتعلمون من خلال التجارب والتفاعلات التي أجروها مع الناس في حياتهم
as well as their surroundings.
فضلا عن محيطهم.
For example.
على سبيل المثال.
When you respond to your baby's cry.
عندما تستجيب لبكاء طفلك.
Your baby learns that you love her.
تتعلم طفلتك أنكِ تحبيها.
And care for her.
وتعتني بها.
And when you cuddle smile at your baby.
وعندما تحتضنين او تبتسمي لطفلك.
It releases chemicals in your baby's body
يطلق ذلك مواد كيميائية في جسم طفلك
which makes him feel good
مما يجعله يشعر بالرضا
and helps him bond with you.
ويساعده على الارتباط بك.
The experiences and interactions you share with your baby
تشكل الخبرات والتفاعلات التي تشاركها مع طفلك ملايين الروابط في دماغه
your relationship with your baby helps her develop the skills she needs for life.
علاقتك بطفلك تساعده على تطوير المهارات التي يحتاجها مدى الحياة.
Settling and comforting your baby helps him trust and rely on you
إن تهدئة و تسلية طفلك يساعده على الثقة بك والاعتماد عليك
and gives him confidence to form relationships with other people.
ويمنحه الثقة لتكوين علاقات مع الآخرين.
Noticing and responding to your baby's needs helps calm and settle her.
تساعد ملاحظة احتياجات طفلك والاستجابة لها على تهدئته واستقراره.
So she can do other things like play or sleep.
حتى تتمكن من القيام بأشياء أخرى مثل اللعب أو النوم.
Even if you don't know why your baby is unsettled will crying.
حتى لو كنت لا تعرفين سبب عدم هدؤ او بكاء طفلك.
It's important to comfort her.
من المهم أن تريحها.
Picking her up
حملها,
cuddling her
عناقها
and talking to her in a gentle voice
والتحدث معها بصوت لطيف
makes her feel secure and loved.
يجعلها تشعر بالأمان والحب.
Play is a great way to interact with your baby and help her to learn and feel loved.
اللعب طريقة رائعة للتفاعل مع طفلك ومساعدته على التعلم والشعور بالحب.
And at this age
وفي هذا العمر
the best toy for your baby is you.
أفضل لعبة لطفلك هي أنت.
Games like peek-a-boo stimulate your baby's brain
ألعاب مثل الغميضة تحفز دماغ طفلك
and help him develop important skills like thinking.
تساعده على تطوير مهارات مهمة مثل التفكير.
Communicating.
التواصل.
Socializing
الاجتماعية والتحرك.
You can play with your baby anywhere and everywhere.
يمكنك اللعب مع طفلك في أي مكان وفي كل مكان.
Everything is new to your baby.
كل شيء جديد لطفلك.
Singing telling stories doing tummy time.
الغناء و قص القصص و تخصيص وقت للعب.
Talking or making funny sounds a great place to play with your baby.
التحدث أو إصدار أصوات مضحكة , تُعد طُرق رائعًا لللهو مع طفلك.
Your baby loves hearing your voice go up and down and watching your facial
يحب طفلك سماع صوتك يرتفع وينخفض
And even though he can't talk yet he is an excellent communicator.
وعلى الرغم من أنه لا يستطيع التحدث بعد ، فهو محاور ممتاز.
Talking, listening, and responding to him
التحدث والاستماع والرد عليه
builds his language and communication skills.
يبني لغته ومهارات الاتصال لديه.
Your baby is an amazing learner.
طفلك متعلم رائع.
She's learning new things all the time through the everyday things you do together.
إنها تتعلم أشياء جديدة طوال الوقت من خلال الأشياء اليومية التي تقومان بها معًا.
By playing with her and comforting her
من خلال اللعب معها وتهدئتها ،
you're giving your baby a great start in life.
فإنك تمنح طفلك بداية رائعة في الحياة.